{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The resistivity of copper is:", "opta": "9.9", "optb": "10.7", "optc": "16.7", "optd": "17.0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How do fixed resistors usually fail?", "opta": "slowly over time", "optb": "by increasing their value", "optc": "by becoming an open circuit", "optd": "by increasing their value and becoming an open circuit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With Ohm's law, if voltage increases and resistance stays the same:", "opta": "current remains the same", "optb": "power decreases", "optc": "current increases", "optd": "resistance decreases", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which formula shows a direct proportionality between power and voltage?", "opta": "V = IR", "optb": "P = VI", "optc": "P = IR", "optd": "I = V/R", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With 1 mA of current, what wattage rating should a 470 ohm resistor have?", "opta": "1/4 watt", "optb": "1/2 watt", "optc": "1 watt", "optd": "2 watts", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is a 3.9 k resistor color-coded?", "opta": "red, white, red, gold", "optb": "red, green, orange, silver", "optc": "orange, white, red, gold", "optd": "orange, green, orange, silver", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What resistor type is found in SIPs and DIPs?", "opta": "metal film", "optb": "wirewound", "optc": "metal oxide", "optd": "thick film", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ohm's law is not:", "opta": "V = IR", "optb": "I = V/R", "optc": "R = IV", "optd": "R = V/I", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the two major categories for resistors?", "opta": "low and high ohmic value", "optb": "commercial and industrial", "optc": "low and high power value", "optd": "fixed and variable", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many connections does a potentiometer have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "A potentiometer uses three connections, as opposed to a rheostat, which only employs two. Having three connections allows the potentiometer to vary voltage. Both the potentiometer and the rheostat are classified as variable resistors."}, {"question": "What current is flowing in the circuit?", "opta": "288 kA", "optb": "2 kA", "optc": "50 mA", "optd": "500 A", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The six basic forms of energy are:", "opta": "light, sun, magnetic, chemical, electrical, and mechanical", "optb": "electrical, mechanical, light, heat, magnetic, and chemical", "optc": "electrical, mechanical, sun, heat, chemical, and light", "optd": "potential, sun, light, chemical, electrical, and mechanical", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How much energy is stored if 6.24 x 1018 electrons are stored in 4 volts?", "opta": "4 joules", "optb": "1.56 x 1018 electrons", "optc": "1.56 coulombs", "optd": "2.496 x 1019 electrons", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With Ohm's law:", "opta": "current is inversely proportional to resistance", "optb": "resistance is directly proportional to voltage", "optc": "voltage is indirectly proportional to power", "optd": "current is directly proportional to resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power is defined as:", "opta": "the rate at which energy is used", "optb": "watts", "optc": "energy", "optd": "the rate at which energy is generated", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the most commonly used conductor in electronics?", "opta": "aluminum", "optb": "copper", "optc": "gold", "optd": "silver", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With Ohm's law, no change in resistance means that current and voltage will be:", "opta": "directly proportional", "optb": "unable to produce energy", "optc": "the same", "optd": "inversely proportional", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A potentiometer has how many leads?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the ratio of 13 to 47 expressed in percent?", "opta": "2.76%", "optb": "27.7%", "optc": "3.60%", "optd": "36.1%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What happens to current and resistance if the voltage doubles?", "opta": "Current doubles and resistance doubles.", "optb": "Current doubles and resistance is halved.", "optc": "Current remains the same and resistance doubles.", "optd": "Current doubles and resistance remains the same.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One problem with mechanically variable resistors is noticeable in audio circuits as:", "opta": "scratchy noise", "optb": "lack of bass response", "optc": "variable volume", "optd": "too much treble response", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A color code of orange, orange, orange is for what ohmic value?", "opta": "22 kilohms", "optb": "3300 ohms", "optc": "44000 ohms", "optd": "33 kilohms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A conductor's cross-sectional area in circular mils for  inch is:", "opta": "500 cmils", "optb": "100,000 cmils", "optc": "1,000,000 cmils", "optd": "500,000,000 cmils", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a variable resistor's resistance varies in a nonuniform manner as the shaft is moved, it is considered to be:", "opta": "linear", "optb": "defective", "optc": "not wirewound", "optd": "tapered", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Power is measured in units of:", "opta": "joules x charge", "optb": "joules/work", "optc": "joules x voltage", "optd": "joules/time", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many basic types of resistors exist?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "With a complex circuit, a supply source senses:", "opta": "open circuit components", "optb": "when voltages need to be increased", "optc": "only a single resistive connection", "optd": "when complex currents are needed", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many ohms of resistance allows a current of 720 A to flow when 3.6 kV is applied?", "opta": "200 n", "optb": "5 k", "optc": "200 k", "optd": "5 M", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the most important step utilized when measuring resistors?", "opta": "use the highest possible scale", "optb": "keep test leads short", "optc": "zero the meter before using", "optd": "remove power from the circuit", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Components designed to oppose the flow of current are called:", "opta": "insulators", "optb": "conductors", "optc": "resistors", "optd": "heat exchangers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many amps are used by a 100 watt, 120 volt light bulb?", "opta": "1.2 amps", "optb": "12000 amps", "optc": "830 mA", "optd": "12 amps", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The source is 24 volts and the load resistance is 100 . What is the load current?", "opta": "2.4 A", "optb": "240 mA", "optc": "24 mA", "optd": "2.4 mA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistors are identified as to wattage by:", "opta": "size", "optb": "color code", "optc": "types of materials", "optd": "internal construction", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What type of resistors have a tolerance rating of 5% or greater?", "opta": "precision", "optb": "SIP", "optc": "general-purpose", "optd": "wirewound", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistor tolerance is either printed on the component, or is provided by:", "opta": "keyed containers", "optb": "size", "optc": "color code", "optd": "ohmmeter reading", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many connections does a rheostat have?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are the parts of a rheostat?", "opta": "wiper and resistor track", "optb": "solenoid and armature", "optc": "contact and wire wound", "optd": "center tape and wiper", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The load resistance increases. How will the load current change?", "opta": "vary", "optb": "remain constant", "optc": "increase", "optd": "decrease", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the power dissipated by a 1.2 k resistor with 12 volts across it?", "opta": "12 W", "optb": "1.2 W", "optc": ".12 W", "optd": "12 mW", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many joules of energy will a 10 W lamp dissipate in one minute?", "opta": "10 joules", "optb": "60 joules", "optc": "600 joules", "optd": "3600 joules", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which type of test equipment is used to measure resistors?", "opta": "ohmmeter", "optb": "ammeter", "optc": "voltmeter", "optd": "watt meter", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance is:", "opta": "the opposition to current flow accompanied by the dissipation of heat", "optb": "symbolized by R, measured in ohms, and directly proportional to conductance", "optc": "directly proportional to current and voltage", "optd": "represented by the flow of fluid in the fluid circuit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Electrical equipment is protected against excessive current by a(n):", "opta": "fusible wire link", "optb": "insulated glass container", "optc": "metal ended coil", "optd": "circuit opener", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If resistance decreases, then current will:", "opta": "decrease", "optb": "increase", "optc": "remain the same", "optd": "double", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A wire with a smaller cross-sectional area will produce:", "opta": "less heat", "optb": "more conductance", "optc": "less resistance", "optd": "more heat", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 22-gauge wire will have a diameter in mils of:", "opta": "10.03", "optb": "22.35", "optc": "45.26", "optd": "71.96", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The word work means that:", "opta": "energy has been transferred", "optb": "it is inversely related to energy", "optc": "no energy has been transferred", "optd": "work and energy are not related", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A good fuse will have:", "opta": "zero ohms resistance", "optb": "a medium resistance", "optc": "a high resistance", "optd": "an infinite resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What property does an incandescent lamp possess?", "opta": "cold resistance", "optb": "hot resistance", "optc": "ballast resistance", "optd": "both cold and hot resistance", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One advantage of a carbon film resistor over a carbon composition resistor is:", "opta": "less circuit noise", "optb": "smaller size", "optc": "higher wattage", "optd": "poor tolerance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a metallic conductor has a positive temperature coefficient of resistance, then:", "opta": "as temperature increases, resistance decreases", "optb": "as current increases, resistance decreases", "optc": "as voltage increases, current increases", "optd": "as temperature increases, resistance increases", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What value of a  1.3 k resistor as measured by a digital voltmeter would be considered within tolerance?", "opta": "1234", "optb": "1235", "optc": "1366", "optd": "1367", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a calculator display was \"0.00263,\" what would this answer be in percent?", "opta": "0.026%", "optb": "0.26%", "optc": "2.63%", "optd": "26.3%", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A 33 k resistor with a 20% tolerance checks out as ok with which of the following ohmmeter readings?", "opta": "26400 ohms", "optb": "24183 ohms", "optc": "6600 ohms", "optd": "39970 ohms", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For P = V2/R, a decrease in resistance should produce:", "opta": "a decrease in power", "optb": "an increase in ohms", "optc": "an increase in power", "optd": "a decrease in current", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "After a lamp is turned on, its filament resistance will change to become:", "opta": "less resistive", "optb": "cooler", "optc": "brighter", "optd": "more resistive", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Wirewound resistors are usually used in circuits that have:", "opta": "high current", "optb": "negative temperature coefficients", "optc": "low power", "optd": "high voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is power dissipated in a resistor?", "opta": "by resistance", "optb": "by voltage", "optc": "by current", "optd": "by heat", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Resistance in a circuit is:", "opta": "opposition to current", "optb": "opposition to voltage", "optc": "the same as current", "optd": "the same as voltage", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The unit designator for resistance value is the:", "opta": "ampere", "optb": "ohm", "optc": "volt", "optd": "watt", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One ampere of current flowing through one ohm of resistance is equal to:", "opta": "1 horsepower", "optb": "1 Btu", "optc": "1 watt", "optd": "1 joule", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Good insulators:", "opta": "have few electrons in their outer shells", "optb": "have a large dielectric strength", "optc": "have a small breakdown voltage", "optd": "have many electrons in the nucleus", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}